Jennifer Cahir

Staff Pharmacist at Medco Health Solutions, Inc.

Hainesport, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Jennifer-Cahir/0b3efd1d18082627

Motivated professional with experience in a wide range of pharmaceutical settings including pharmacotherapeutic research, academia, mail order and community dispensing. Possesses strong interpersonal skills, has experience building positive customer and client relationships, and background ensuring customer satisfaction. Learns quickly, has an outstanding knowledge of pharmaceuticals, and has consistently achieved success in exceeding goals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Staff Pharmacist

Medco Health Solutions, Inc - Willingboro, NJ - September 2009 to Present

- Selected to become a project lead within the Center for Pharmacotherapeutic Research.
- Leading a quality improvement initiative to help understand patient barriers to filling new medications via a demonstration project.
- Reviews business requirement documents and final requirement documents with core team members.
- Assists core team in developing a flexible process that allows for iteration to measure and refine targeting algorithms and methodology.
- Assists with gathering data and in consequent activity and outcome reporting to track initial patient feedback and subsequent behavior.
- Returned a proof of concept that patients have receptivity to pharmacist interventions relative to first fill non-adherence.
- Responsible for proving sustainable ROI for providing product.
- Responsible for reviewing, identifying and filtering identified pre-approved parameters for calls and resolving opportunities in designated system.
- Responsible for inputting pertinent patient data into various databases in order to log adverse drug effects and subsequently report that data back to pharmaceutical drug companies.
- Performs various functions within the Therapeutic Resource Center (TRC) including DUR profiling, doctor and patient calls.
- Performs various back-end functions including verifying medications by tablet identification, lot number, and expiration dates, perform technician audits and is responsible for final product verifications.

CVS Pharmacy - Philadelphia, PA - January 2008 to September 2009

Pharmacy Candidate Preceptor

- Worked with 6th year pharmacy candidates in the development of pharmacy skills to better prepare them for a career in pharmacy.
- Helped students create presentations with PowerPoint and Excel spreadsheets on assigned topics relating to pharmaceuticals and specific disease states. Reviewed and edited presentations, checking accuracy of facts and numbers.
- Educated students on patient specific disease states with a specialty in immunology, cardiovascular disease, and renal transplant.
- Worked with students in the evaluation and critiquing of journal articles pertaining to healthcare. Taught students how to read articles and how to pull pertinent information from such articles.
- Received positive evaluations from students during quarterly reviews.

ROTATION EXPERIENCE

CVS Pharmacy - Runnemede, NJ - August 2005 to September 2009

CVS Employee

- January 1999 to September 2009

Pharmacist-In-Charge

- Oversaw the daily compounding and dispensing of pharmaceuticals, taking orders from doctors, reviewing orders for accuracy, and communicating with hospitals and healthcare professionals.
- Selected by district supervisor to manage a training pharmacy for 34 stores; developed new employees into pharmacy sales associates and certified pharmacy technicians; developed graduate interns into pharmacists and pharmacists-in-charge. Trained pharmacists on the compounding and dispensing of pharmaceuticals, paperwork completion, and doctor and hospital follow-up to ensure customer satisfaction in an environment of increased demand.
- Managed a pharmacy staff of 20 employees including technicians and pharmacists; ensured that the daily operations of the pharmacy ran smoothly while ensuring the highest quality of patient care.
- Completed all projects on time, meeting and exceeding company goals; maintaining accuracy and ensuring that all products met state and federal requirements and regulations.
- Established store as number one in the district in customer ratings for 2007-2008.
- Achieved number one position in district in store executionables for 2007-2008 surpassing company standards.
- Established district policies and procedures to ensure accuracy and organization within pharmacy.
- Took part in Pharmacy Care Initiative Program, including coaching and counseling pharmacy personnel in quality of adherence outreach calls.
- Recognized for building strong relationships with customers; many customers requested continued relationships because of product knowledge and ability to answer questions and solve problems.

Novartis Pharmaceuticals Corp - East Hanover, NJ - January 2005 to March 2005

Medical Information-Organ Transplant

- Analyzed and interpreted scientific data to develop comprehensive and accurate documents to appropriately respond to inquiries from healthcare professionals.
- Developed a high level of knowledge in Organ Transplantation in order to effectively respond to healthcare professionals inquiries.
- Developed skills in prioritizing multiple projects and in delivering complete and accurate information within deadlines.

Saint Barnabas Medical Center - Livingston, NJ - October 2004 to November 2004

Renal and Pancreas Transplant Division

- · Participated in inpatient care rounds
- Maintained and updated patients profiles with diagnosis, allergies, and current medications.
- Monitored drug therapy to evaluate appropriateness of use, dose, regimen, and therapeutic duplication.
- Monitored drug therapy and adjusted patients drug regimens based on CrCl and pertinent labs values
- Followed patients listed but not yet transplanted as well as post-transplanted patients to optimize pharmacologic therapy with regards to co-morbid conditions.
- Identified and suggested drug therapy where positive pharmacoeconomic impact could be achieved.

EDUCATION

Doctor of Pharmacy

Ernest Mario School of Pharmacy - Piscataway, NJ 2005

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

KEY SKILLS & EXPERIENCES

- Holds a Doctor of Pharmacy degree.
- Has experience in project leadership
- Has experience in adverse drug event reporting to pharmaceutical drug companies.
- Has experience in managing a pharmacy staff of 20 employees.
- Has background in the development of training modules for pharmacists and ancillary personnel.
- Has background in training pharmacists and ancillary personnel.
- Possesses a strong knowledge of specific disease states including immunology, cardiovascular disease, and renal transplant.
- Completes all projects in a timely manner, exceeding goals and meeting deadlines.
- Varies work activities and responsibilities to accommodate business needs and ensure quality and accuracy, respectively.
- MAGIC(TM) trained